# Joao Moreira

OBoston, MA

joaosomoreira@gmail.com

joaosomoreira.com

<u>+1 (617) 992-5697</u>

#### **Professional Summary**

Software Engineer with more than eight years of experience programming, designing, and delivering reliable, scalable, and tested applications, meeting both customer and business needs. Experience with direct to customer and B2B projects. Comfortable working in teams of any type and size. Experience with line management duties and career development plans.

Javascript, Typescript Python, Django, Flask Golang Redux, NgRx, Alt.js GraphQL, Apollo Client Node.js Angular Ionic, Cordova, Capacitor Java, Spring Boot
PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL
React, React SSR
Karma, Jest, Jasmine
TDD / BDD, DDD
Micro services architecture
Continuous Integration

Continuous Deployment

HTML, Styled Components PHP, Laravel CSS Modules, SASS, LESS Webpack, Gulp, Parcel Jenkins, TeamCity Docker AWS Serverless, Terraform

**Experience** 

### Software Engineer

Current Health | August 2020 - Present

- Worked with the Product and Design teams to design, plan, estimate and develop features across the technology stack in a platform that delivers end to end patient care at home.
- Leading a large team in the development of a completely new version of the health care practitioner mobile app built using fully native technologies in both iOS and Android.
- Part of, and sometimes lead, a team that designed initial concepts and implementation of EMR integration services leveraging Redox Engine for translation of data from HL7 to JSON.
- Integral part of the development of engineering wide processes such as Critical Incident Reviews, L2 Support and Team Showcase and Demo sessions.

Java, Typescript, Python, Spring Boot, Angular, Ionic, Django, AWS, Jenkins, Terraform

#### Lead Front-End Developer

Funeral Guide | January 2019 - July 2020

- Upon joining the company, I established the technology stack for the Frontend, designing, architecting, and developing all the necessary features for launching the Arranger web application in only 2 months.
- Lead the Frontend development team (varying in size between 3 to 7 people) through a series of successful work sprints implementing major features including inventory management and invoicing.
- Provided domain knowledge and technical direction to the entire product team and share Scrum Master responsibilities with the Lead Backend Developer.
- Developed and launched a small reporting gateway to monitor events on the Frontend using Go.
- Performed 1-to-1s, conflict resolution and technical mentorship to members of the Frontend team.

React, ES6, Redux, GraphQL, Apollo Client, PHP, CQRS, Go, AWS Lambda

#### Joao Moreira

#### Senior Front-End Developer

Oneserve Ltd. | October 2017 - December 2018

- Designed, developed, and launched a mobile application from proof of concept to production.
- Implemented the infrastructure around the mobile application leveraging a number of AWS services, including Cognito, DynamoDB, API Gateway and Lambda, all deployed via Serverless.
- Developed the continuous deployment pipeline to validate, build and deploy the mobile application directly to the App Store and Google Play.
- Provided technical direction and mentorship to team members.
- Made open source contributions to Cordova plugin repositories and Ionic Framework tools.

Typescript, Angular 4, Ionic, Redux, AWS, Java, Jenkins

#### Senior Web Developer

Sound in Theory | August 2016 - October 2017

- Developed and launched several websites and storefronts using multiple PHP frameworks.
- Designed, architected, and launched the technology replacement of a back-office quoting engine.
- Designed and built an automated contact form testing framework.

React, Flux, FuelPHP, Magento 2, Laravel, Node.JS, Selenium, Gulp, Apache, Nginx

#### Software Developer

ManyWho Inc. | September 2014 - June 2016

- Contributed to the development of a UI engine to execute and display ManyWho Flows.
- Collaborated with a senior developer in the design, development and launch of a Draw Tool to build workflows.
- Created and launched a small Python Web Service that converts platform metadata into Lua code.
- Designed and implemented workflow solutions using the ManyWho Flow platform and supporting customers on their workflow projects.

React, ES6, Alt.js, Python, Lua

#### Front-End Developer

blur Group | April 2014 - August 2014

- Contributed to the development of the Frontend of platforms and dashboards for customers' use.
- Performed a number of styling and user experience improvements to customer dashboards.

AngularJS, LESS, jQuery

#### Joao Moreira

## Software Engineer

Betweien | March 2013 - April 2014

- Developed several websites, web and mobile applications, including management of the remote servers where all the applications developed were hosted.
- Managed all server infrastructure and oversaw the deployment of mobile applications.

HTML5, Canvas, jQuery, PHP, Apache

#### **Education**

Institute of Engineering of Porto (ISEP), Porto, Portugal BSC Computer Engineering | September 2008 - October 2012

Institute of Engineering of Porto (ISEP), Porto, Portugal iOS Development Course (27 hours) | March 2014 - April 2014